以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将有助于MIT开放课程继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
我们应开始我只想说，这是一个
shall we start let me just say this is a
对我来说是一次伟大的冒险
great adventure for me to be here all on
我自己教授涉及的课程
my own teaching a course that involves
从数据中学习，令人兴奋
learning from data so it's exciting
主题和很多线性代数
subject and a lot of linear algebra goes
进入它所以这是第二道菜
into it so it's sort of a second course
在线性代数我可以
in linear algebra can I just
你会知道什么是有恒星的
you'll know what so there is a stellar
网站建立，将成为
site established and that will be the
我们使用这个基本的东西是公众
basic thing that we use this is a public
网站方法mit.edu
site method mit.edu
从数据中学习，所以有一本书
learning from data and so a book is
未来很快，因为我们说话或
coming pretty quickly as we speak or
在我们发言之后，那个网站就有了
after we speak and that site has the
这本书的目录
table of contents of the book which
会让你知道可能是什么
would give you an idea of what could be
在课程中，我和我打印出一个
in the course and I and I printed out a
只为那一页的每个人复制
copy for everybody just of that one page
这可能是最后的第一个也是最后一个
that's probably the final first and last
可能与表的讲义
handout maybe with with the table of
你会在那里看到的内容
contents which you'll see there and also
你会看到前两个部分
you'll see there the first two sections
这本书的是什么，我会跟
of the book which is what I'll talk
关于今天和一点点
about today and and on a little bit in
到星期五，这是线性的
to Friday so that's that's linear
代数当然是因为课程
algebra of course because the course
有点从线性代数开始
sort of begins with linear algebra
实际上你会知道的事情
actually things that you would know from
1806但是你这是一种说法
1806 but you but this is a way to say
这是非常重要的事情
this is really important stuff so that's
我今天要做什么我想做点什么
what I'll do today I'd like to do some
从今天的线性代数开始
start on the linear algebra today
这是关于这个的重要事实
and here's the great facts about the
当然至少我们知道有这样的我们
course at least we knew there were so we
去年我们几个人教过它
taught it last year several of us
在一起，我们知道不会有
together and we knew there wouldn't be a
期末考试，但我们想象有可能
final exam but we imagined there might
一路上是测验但是我们
be quizzes along the way but then we
想不出什么可以穿上的
couldn't think of anything to put on the
测验，所以我们取消了那些，但你做了
quizzes so we canceled those but you do
尽管如此，我还是学到了很多东西
learn a lot nevertheless and so I guess
我们立足档次的家庭作业等等
we base the grades on the homeworks so
作业将是部分线性的
the homeworks will be partly linear
代数问题，部分在线你
algebra questions and partly online you
知道像识别手写
know like recognizing handwriting
将图像拼接在一起很多其他
stitching images together many other
事情，我会像我们一样谈论这些事情
things and I'll talk about those as we
好吧是的
go right good yeah
所以这就是一般情况和
so this that's the general picture and
今天我会说更多，我可以
I'll say more about it today and I could
回答任何关于它的问题所以我们是
answer any question about it so we're
录像带，如果有人的话
getting videotaped so if anybody's
害羞地坐在远处，但它会
bashful sit at the far back but it'll be
有趣的是啊，你可知道视频
fun yeah you may know the videos for
1806所以这就像下一步1806
1806 so this is like the next step 1806
五，这对我来说非常令人兴奋
five that's pretty exciting for me so
任何问题或我应该做一些数学
any question or shall I do a little math
为什么不然后我会说一个
why not and then and then I'll say a
多一点对课程只是让你
little more about the course just so you
知道前方是什么，是的
have an idea of what what's ahead yeah
它看起来就像这个房间
and it looks like this room is exactly
对我来说合适的尺寸所以我很高兴
the right size to me so I'm pleased okay
那么线性代数的交易是什么呢？
so so what's the deal in linear algebra
如果我开始的话，让我开始原谅我
let me I'll start forgive me if I start
与我做的第一天
with what I do the very first day in
1806将矩阵乘以a
1806 which is multiply a matrix by a
矢量然后我就毕业
vector and then I'll graduate to
将矩阵乘以5月
multiplying a matrix by a May
这样的技巧，你会说我知道
tricks so that and you will say I know
那些东西，但你知道它是正确的
that stuff but do you know it the right
你说，乘法
way do you think of the multiplication
正确的方式让我告诉你我的意思
the right way so let me tell you what I
相信是正确的做法太让我
believe to be the right way so let me
拿一个矩阵说两三五一一
take a matrix say two three five one one
七，三四十二好吧
seven and three four twelve okay and
我总是把矩阵称为好
I'll always call matrices a okay so
第一步只是X次的一次
first step is just a times X a times a
矢量所以我乘以a乘以说x1
vector so I multiply a a by let's say x1
x2x3以及如何查看答案
x2 x3 and how do I look at that answer
所以选择是想想行
so the choice is think of the rows of
矩阵或想到列和
the matrix or think of the columns and
如果你想到的行是
if you think of the rows which is the
标准的乘法方式
standard way to multiply you would take
点积，因此第一种方式是
the dot product so the first way is the
第一种方式是RowRow的点积
first way is dot product of Row Row
点缀着X右2X1加X2plus
dotted with X right 2 X 1 plus X 2 plus
3X3它给你答案a
3 X 3 it gives you the answer a
组件在低级别的时间
component at a time that's the low level
看待它的好方法就是矢量
way the good way to see it is vector
明智地看到这个X1倍增
wise see this as X 1 multiplies that
第一列X是第二列的2倍
first column X 2 times the second column
117和X3倍于第三列34
1 1 7 and X 3 times the third column 3 4
好，所以它是矢量的组合
good so it's a combination of vectors
当然它会产生一个矢量和
and of course it produces a vector and
在这里，我们有一个三点矩阵和三个
here we have a three by three matrix and
我们的载体在r3和大多数载体中
our vectors are in r3 and most vectors
将在R3或RN本课程使
will be in r3 or RN for this course so
这是正确的答案，当然
that's the right answer and of course
第一个分量是2X1+1X2+3
the first component is 2 X 1 + 1 X 2 + 3
X3相同的213相同的点积
X 3 the same 2 1 3 the same dot product
出来正确，但你看它就像排序
comes out right but you see it like sort
各一次，而不是零碎所以
of all at once instead of piecemeal so
那是你知道课程的一部分我
that's you know part of the course I
猜猜我希望得到的部分内容
guess part of what I hope to get across
正在考虑矩阵矩阵作为
is thinking of a matrix of a matrix as a
整件事不仅仅是一堆9或者
whole thing not just a bunch of 9 or or
M乘以n个数字，但将其视为
M times n numbers but thinking of it as
a矩阵乘以a
a as a thing a matrix multiplies a
向量给另一个向量是的想
vector to give another vector yeah think
所以，当我说斧头你
so that when I say ax that you
马上立刻想到你
immediately think that you immediately
认为好的斧头有一个明确的含义它是一个
think okay ax has a clear meaning it's a
现在这样的列的组合
combination of the columns of a so now
让我采取下一步和下一步
let me take that next step and the next
步骤是考虑所有的组合
step is think about all combinations of
我们采用矩阵a的列
the columns of a we take the matrix a
我们采取所有的X，我们想象所有
and we take all X's and we imagine all
输出和我想问你的意思
the outputs and what I want to ask you
是是什么样子，如果我只是
is what does that look like if I just
取1X1向量XI得到一个向量
take 1 X 1 vector X I get a vector
输出将矢量传递给矢量但是
output takes a vector to a vector but
现在我把所有的X都拿走了
now I take all X's the hole all of
矢量X在3d中或在3d中我得到了所有
vectors X in or in 3d and I get all
这些答案我想起了所有这些
these answers and I think of them all
在一起，所以我有一堆
together and so I've got a bunch of
实际上向量无限多个向量
vectors infinitely many vectors actually
问题是如果我绘制那些
and the question is what if I plot those
无限多的向量我有什么
infinitely many vectors what do I have
线性代数的美妙之处在于
and the beauty of linear algebra is that
像这样的问题
questions like this
你可以回答他们，他们就是你
you can answer them and they you
直观地看到你肯定会看到它
intuitively see it you certainly see it
在3D中，你有权利和
in 3d and you kind of have the right and
正确的想法甚至十个维度
the right idea in ten dimensions even
虽然我们大多数人看不太清楚
though most of us don't see too well in
在我们的10中10D但在这里我们得到了3个
10 D in our 10 but here we got three
好的，所以你看到我在说什么
okay so so do you see what I'm saying
我现在把所有的X都拿走，所以一切都是X.
I'm taking all X's so now so all a X
给了我们一大堆矢量和那些
gives us a big bunch of vectors and that
载体的集合称为
collection of vectors is called the
它的列空间是其他的空间
column space of a it's a space in other
这是那里的关键词
words that that's the keyword there the
a的列空间，我只会写它
column space of a and I'll just write it
当我需要一封信的时候，作为一个C的
as C of a when I need a letters for it
好的，所以我会问你是做什么的
okay so I'm going to ask you what does
这个列空间看起来像那样
this column space look like and that
有时取决于矩阵
depends on the matrix sometimes the
列空间将是整个r3
column space would be the whole of r3
有时它是r3或更小的一组
sometimes it's a smaller set in r3 or
空间
space
你知道在这种情况下它是什么吗？
do you know what it is in this case do I
得到我从这些家伙得到所有的3D
get do I get all of 3d out of these guys
通过选择所有X1和X2以及X3
by choosing all X 1 and X 2 and X 3 it
似乎它是一个随机矩阵
seemed like if it was a random matrix
答案肯定是肯定的，如果
the answer would be surely yes if the
随机3x3矩阵是它的列空间
random 3x3 matrix is its column space is
将成为我们三个栏目中的所有栏目
going to be all of our three its columns
将是独立的行
are going to be independent its rows are
将会是独立的
going to be independent it's going to be
可逆的它会变得很棒但是
invertible it's going to be great but is
这个矩阵是什么与基质回事
this matrix what's up with that matrix
不，这不对
no it's not right
所以我得到了什么，而不是我们所有的
so what do I get instead of all of our
三，如果你得到那架飞机，我会得到一架飞机
three I get a plane yeah if you get that
在望所以采取所有X
in sight so by taking all X's
每个人都和我在一起所有X都是如此
everybody's with me all X's here so so
这意味着像它填充
that means that like it fills in
无论如何，因为它是线性的
whatever and well because it's linear
代数它可能会成为我们所有人
algebra it's gonna be likely all of our
三
three
是什么让我的飞机甚至是一条线
or a plane or even a line what let me
在这里揍一会儿
just bat over here for a moment
给我一个矩阵，其中的
give me a matrix which would whose
列空间只是一行
column space would only be a line all
一个人还好，哇，这让我活了下来
one's okay wow that's a let me liven it
上三点三三八
up a little three three three eight
八，八我觉得还好，所以我想
eight eight I think okay so I think that
这些列的组合是
the combinations of those columns are
所有在同一条线上看起来就是这样
all on the same line look that says that
列空间只是一行而我
the column space is just a line and I
然后会说矩阵这么一个
would say then that the matrix so a
这个a的列空间是另一行
column space of this a is a line another
我可以说这就是排名
way I could say this is that the rank of
矩阵是等级的一种
the matrix is one the rank is sort of
列空间的维度很好
the dimension of the column space well
不排序的，这就是它是排名
not sort of that's what it is the rank
在塔的尺寸看
is the dimension of the column see
每个人都看到你得到一条线
everybody sees that you get a line
因为任何组合x1加上
because any combination x1 of that plus
其中x2加x3即将发生
x2 of that plus x3 of that is is going
沿着这条线进入这里是
to go in in along that line here's the
第一列是第二列
first column here's the second column
他们都在一条线上所以我永远不会得到
they're all on a line so I'll never get
如果我允许所有的X，那就离开那条线
off that line if I allow all X's I'll
得到整条线
get the whole line
现在在这里你说的不是正确的
now here you said not a line right what
这是什么是列空间
was what was the column space for this
帅哥现在为什么不是我们所有人
guy plain now why isn't it all of our
三，你看到了什么是什么
three what what is what do you see that
特别的，因为它很特别
special there because it is special
这使得列空间变得有点像
that's making the column space sort of
特别是飞机而不是整体
special a plane instead of the whole
事情是的，这三个是怎么回事
thing yeah what's up with these three
列第三列是总和
columns the third column is the sum of
这两个这样的第一列是罚款
these two so the first column is fine to
3/5秒列是不同的
3/5 second column is in a different
方向，当我采取组合
direction and when I take combinations
我会得到前两列的内容
of the first two columns what will I get
很抱歉继续问你的问题但是
sorry to keep asking your questions but
就是这样
that's that's
反正这是我一直做下去，从而使
anyway that's what I always do so so so
毛皮是那些第一组合
the fur the combinations of those first
两列是一架飞机，因为它们是
two columns are a plane because they're
在不同的人看到的那种
in different everybody kind of sees that
图片我们已经有一列了
picture we've got one column one going
那样，叫他们走那条路
that way and call them to go in that way
然后，如果我采取任何倍数
and then if I take any multiple of
列一个我有一整行的任何
column one I've got a whole line any
第二列的倍数然后当我
multiple of column two and then when I
把它们放在一起就填满了
put the two together it fills in the
填写飞机是的，是的，我们的耳朵
fills in the plane yeah yeah our ear
直觉说这是对的所以这是一个
intuition says that's right so this is a
排名矩阵是什么排名
matrix of rank what's the rank of this
矩阵二，因为它有两个
matrix two because it's got two
独立的列，但第三列
independent columns but the third column
是依赖第三列是
is dependent the third column is a
这是其他人的组合
combination of the others so this is
像这样的矩阵真的是
matrices like this are really the
线性代数的构建块
building blocks of linear algebra
它们是数据的构建块
they're the building blocks of data
科学他们是一个矩阵和
science they're rank one matrices and
让我告诉你一个特殊的方式来思考
let me show you a special way to think
写下我认为的那些排名第一的矩阵
write those rank one matrices I think of
该矩阵作为列向量111次
this matrix as column vector 1 1 1 times
行向量138所以它是一列
the row vector 1 3 8 so it's a column
乘以排名第一的矩阵
times a row that's a rank one matrix do
你知道这是真的
you see that it's a that's a true
乘法它看起来有点
multiplication there it looks a little
奇怪，但它是一个三个矩阵
weird but it's a three by one matrix
乘以这些数字的1乘3矩阵
times a 1 by 3 matrix these numbers have
是相同的，然后输出是3
to be the same and then the output is 3
3，就是这样，你看到了它
by 3 and it's that and you see that it
因此，我将继续这样做
factors so I'm going to move on to that
想法下一个想法即将到来
idea the next idea coming up will be
我们可以很好地看到那个
that that we we can see well that's
即将到来，我们将看到矩阵
coming that we're going to see matrices
有两个因素好吧让我让我
in with two factors okay let me let me
移动到那，但他们回来了
move to that but but they're back for
这个原始矩阵
this original matrix
好吧，这个专栏是什么
okay so what's with this the column
如果我现在想的话，空间就是一架飞机
space is a plane so if I think about now
独立列的关键思想如何
the key idea of independent columns how
我来到这里有很多独立专栏
many independent columns have I got here
如果我想要更正到第三列
to correct to the third column if I want
特别挑选那个，所以我
to especially pick on that one so I
经常从左到右，所以我会说
often go left to right so I'll say the
第一个家伙的好第二个人的好
first guy's good second guy's good the
第三个家伙不是独立的
third guy not is not independent of the
其他所以我只有两个独立的
others so I just have two independent
列和那些是那两列
columns and those are those two columns
这将是列空间的基础
would be a basis for the column space so
这就像是关键的想法
that's the like the critical idea of
你计算的线性代数
linear algebra that's what you compute
与你找到一个基础和每一个
with you find a basis and and every
列空间中的东西是一个
thing in the column space is a
包括那些在内的这些组合
combination of these including that is
这也已经是一个组合了
also that's already a combination of
除了列中的其他所有内容
those but everything else in the column
空间是这两者的组合所以
space is a combination of those two so
所以有一个基础可以，所以你有
so there a basis for it okay so you have
你有这个想法的时代X的想法
the idea of a times X you have the idea
允许所有XS的列空间
of column space of a which allows all XS
那么现在我们正在进入这个想法
then now we're moving into the idea of
独立列和数量
independent columns and the number of
独立柱是为秩如此
independent columns is is the rank so
我应该把这个等级写在某个地方
the rank shall I write that somewhere
也许这里的排名是多少
maybe here the rank is the number of
独立专栏
independent columns
而现在这是什么意思的
and right now what do I mean by
独立专栏让我们看看
independent columns well let's just see
通过使用它意味着什么呢？
what that means by by using it are we
好我知道我在这里回顾但是
good I'm I know I'm reviewing here but
请允许我参加第一堂课和第一堂课
allow me for this first class and part
下次还要复习，但你会
of next time also to review but you'll
看到一些新的事实为什么我们不看
see something new fact why don't we see
马上就有新东西让我跟随
something new right away let me follow
上现出了独立的想法
up on the idea of Independence in a
系统的方式所以这里是我的矩阵一个罐头
systematic way so here's my matrix a can
我再写两三五一
I write that again two three five one
一七，这家伙是他的总和
one seven and this guy was the sum of
那些好了，所以这是我的矩阵确定，所以
those okay so that's my matrix a ok so
让我们从头开始，找到一个
let's start from scratch and find a
中的列空间的基础
basis for the column space in in the
最自然的方式，所以我要带
most natural way so I'm going to take a
基础我会找到什么基础a
basis I'm going to what's a basis a
基础是独立的列所以
basis is independent columns so all
三个一起不会成为基础而是
three together would not be a basis but
必须不仅仅是独立的
there have to be not just independent
但他们必须填补空间
but but they have to fill the space
他们的组合必须填补
their combinations have to fill the
所以二三五可以让我们这么说
space so so two three five can let's say
我想创建一个我称之为的基础
I want to create a basis I'll call the
矩阵C的列的列的基础
matrix C column a basis for the column
空间，所以这是一个自然的方式来做到这一点我
space so here's a natural way to do it I
看看第一列它不是零
look at the first column it's not zeros
如果它全是零我不想要那个
if it was all zeros I wouldn't want that
在一个基础上但不是我把它放进去
in a basis but it's not so I put it in
这是我基础中的第一个向量
so that's the first vector in my basis
如果，我继续进入第二列
then I go on to the second column if
那个专栏是四点六十分
that column was four six ten what would
如果第二列是四六，那我就这样做
I do if that second column was four six
十，我会把它放在基础上，但是
ten would I put it in the basis no but
一个七个就可以了
one one seven is okay right one one
七是
seven is
不同的方向它不是一个
different direction it's not a
什么，我们已经有了这样的组合
combination of what we've already got so
我说好的，增加了新的东西
I say okay that adds something new put
然后我转到第三栏
it in then I move on to the third column
我把它放在你知道的基础上
do I put that into a basis you know the
答案现在没有，因为我期待
answer by now no because I'm looking to
看到这是这些家伙的组合
see is it a combination of these guys
它是其中之一
and it is it's one of that plus one of
所以它不是独立的，所以我
that so it's not independent so I've
我现在已经完成了我有一个矩阵C.
I've finished now I've got a matrix C
这就像直接从a和
which was like taken directly from a and
我只保留了独立的列和我
I kept only independent columns and I
从左到右工作，我可以看到
worked from left to right and I can see
这马上现在的等级是
that right away now that the rank is to
列列我应该说列
the column rank I should say the column
排名一些独立的列是
rank a number of independent columns is
太好了，现在是我要走的关键一步
too good now comes a key step I'm gonna
产生第三个正在进行的矩阵R.
produce a third matrix R which is going
告诉我如何从这些列中获取这些列
to tell me how to get these columns from
这些列及其形状将会发生
these columns and its shape is going to
做好它的形状我没有
be well its shape I don't have any
选择这是3乘2所以R必须是
choice this is 3 by 2 so R has to be to
买东西，所以我喜欢我
buy something so so so I'm like so I
猜猜它必须是2比3，因为我想要
guess it has to be 2 by 3 because I want
以这种方式出现2乘3我是什么
to come out this way 2 by 3 what am I
要在这里做，我只是要投入
gonna do here I'm just going to put in
这些数字是正确的
the numbers are that make this correct
所以这是第一个矩阵分解
so this is a first matrix factorization
它不是很好，它是一个着名的
it's not well it is a famous one
实际上，当我们看到它时，我们会认出来
actually when we see it we'll recognize
它是什么，它是，但它出名了
what it is it's but it's famous in
现在教授近代数
teaching the near algebra but now
实际上看时间是列时间
actually see times are columns times
行已经变得非常重要了
rows has become very very important in
大规模数值线性代数
large scale numerical linear algebra
是的，让我们弄清楚会发生什么
yeah so let's figure out what goes into
我们还好，所以我在做什么
our okay so what's going in what am I
想在这里我把我们的那
thinking here I'm putting in our that
tel所以这些列中的每一列都是
tel so every one of these columns is a
这些就是整体的组合
combination of these that's the whole
我只想把它放进去
point and I'm just going to put in the
你需要的数字，以便进行什么
numbers that you need so what goes in
我们的第一列是什么
the first column of our what goes in the
我们的第一栏，所以我想看看
first column of our so I want to look
那个专栏和那个专栏的组合
what combination of that column and that
专栏给了我这一个是零
column gives me this one yeah one zero
一零，因为你记得我们是怎样的
one zero because you remember how we
当I时，将矩阵乘以向量
multiply a matrix by a vector when I
将该矩阵乘以该向量I.
multiply that matrix by that vector I
取其中一个加零，我看到了
take one of this plus zero of that I see
它是矢量明智的，当然我明白了
it vector wise and of course I get it
对，第二栏怎么样？
right and what about the second column
的R所以第二列应是
of R so the second column should be the
产生第二个的组合
combination that produces the second
正确的列将是什么
column of a correctly what will that be
零谢谢，最后是第三个
zero one thanks and finally the third
第一栏是的，因为其中之一
column one one yes right because one of
加上其中一个产生第三个
this plus one of this produces the third
所以我所做的一切都放在了
column so so all I did was put in the
正确的数字真的是对的
right numbers there really right and
这是正确的，现在SC乘以R等等
this is correct now a SC times R and so
这就像我在这里所做的那样
that's this is like what I've done here
就像前两页一节
is like the first two pages of section
这些说明中的1.1如此1.1和实际上
1.1 in these notes so 1.1 and actually
所以我直截了当地告诉你发生了什么
so I tell you literally what happened
今年早些时候我希望我写这个
earlier this year I wish this I wrote I
用另一个例子写下来
wrote this down with a different example
然后我意识到了那个
and then I realized something that that
坐在我面前的是
sitting here in front of me was the
线性代数中的第一个大定理
first great theorem in linear algebra
列等于等于的事实
the fact that the column rank equals the
排名如果我有一个事实
row rank the fact that if I have a
矩阵，那列加上那个
matrix where that column plus that
专栏给了那一个哦，我是什么
column gives that one oh so what am I
要说这里我变得紧张
going to say here I'm getting nervous
我相信它的组合
about it I believe that a combination of
行给出0你相信我吗？
the rows gives 0 do you believe that I
意味着你必须相信它，这是像
mean you got to believe it this is like
矩阵不是线性代数
a linear algebra the matrix is not
可逆的是方形而是列
invertible it's square but the columns
是依赖所以行必须是
are dependent so the rows have to be
依赖，我不完全看到我
dependent and I don't exactly see I
那个行和。的某种组合
there's some combination of that row and
该行中给出了一个，当我
that row that gives that one and when I
当然，当我看第一个
of course when I looked at the first
专栏中，我想确定它的将是
column I thought ok it's going to be
这将成为其中的太容易了一个
it's going to be too easy one of that
其中一个给了那个，但后来我的
and one of that gives that but then my I
我去了第二栏
went over to the second column and I
意识到这根本不容易，所以你是
realize it's not easy at all so you're
有权拿出你的手机
entitled to pull out a your phone and
想出这个，但有一些该死的
figure this out but there is some damn
这两行的组合
combination of those of those two rows
它给人的第三排它的，否则
it gives the third row it's otherwise
就像课程结束我们停下来但很好
like the course is over we stop but well
也许我们会找到它或以某种方式
maybe we're gonna find it or somehow
是啊是啊所以所以这是这是
yeah yeah so so that's this is the
定理，所以我必须告诉你我
theorem so I so I have to tell you I
意思是你知道我真的很高兴
mean you know I was like really pleased
所以前两页还有两个
so the first two pages got two more
页面跟进那个想法
pages to follow up on that idea that
在这里我们看到的东西，我
here we were seeing something that I
有点证明在1806年，但你不知道
sort of proved in 1806 but not you know
没有在第一讲这是肯定的
not in the first lecture that's for sure
而且我现在也许不是那么清楚
and I'm not not maybe so clearly but now
我可以尝试证明这一点
I can I try to prove it
某某，所以这里不会有
so and so here's the there won't be a
这个课程中有很多证明，但这是
lot of proofs in this class but this is
这样一个重要的事实是等于CR
such an important fact a equals CR is
重要的分解和出
important factorization and and out of
它我们可以连接它们，所以我是什么
it we can connect them so what am I
说我就是那么说的
saying I'm saying that all that that
那排是什么排排名是啊
that the row so what's the row rank yeah
我可以回到这里，这是什么行
I could go back up here what's the row
排行什么是行空间所以行
rank what's the row space so the row
排名将是明确的
rank is going to be the definite the
那个空间的尺寸让我看看
dimension of that space so so I look at
我矩阵是什么的行空间
my matrix a what's the row space of a
我现在可能会看看它的行
I'm gonna look at its rows now maybe
所以我们没有得到一个全新的信件
just so we don't get a whole new letters
对于那里的行空间我是给我的
for the row space there I'm for me the
的一个矩阵的行的空间，以便所以第一
row space of a of a matrix so so first
所有这些都用语言告诉我它是什么
of all tell me in words what it is
什么是矩阵的行空间
what's the row space of the matrix all
所有行的组合
combinations of the rows all
这些行的组合
combinations of the rows that's the
太空所以我会采取所有组合
space so I would take all combinations
那些行来获得组合
of those rows to get combinations of the
我有两种方法可以获得
rows I well two ways I can get
行和方式的组合
combinations of the rows and the way
我会这样做的
I'll do it is
我只是将矩阵转置为那些
I'll just transpose the matrix so those
行变为列，然后我回来
rows become columns and then I'm back to
我做了什么，所以a的行空间是
what I did so the row space of a is the
转置的列空间和这个
column space of a transpose and and this
我们没有优势
has the advantage that we don't
介绍一封新信，这样就可以了
introduce a new letter so it's it'll be
转置的列空间，所以我们
the column space of a transpose so we
不要介绍我们保留的新信
don't introduce a new letter we keep the
传统是列的惯例
convention that vectors are column
矢量将是MATLAB和
vectors which would be the MATLAB and
和朱莉娅和Python的惯例是这样的
and Julia and Python convention so is
没关系
that okay
行空间是组合
the row space is the combination of
这些行，但我会翻转我会做出来的
these rows but I'll flip i'll make them
站起来21322B列向量所以
stand up 2 1 3 2 2 B column vectors so
这是一个完全不同的空间，
it's a totally different space and
实际上在我身上我碰巧拿3乘3
actually in my I happen to take a 3 by 3
示例，以便列空间是一部分
example so that the column space is part
我们的三个和行空间也是
of our three and the row space is also
我们三个的一部分，因为我的矩阵是
part of our three because my matrix is
三个三个更好的例子我的意思
three by three a better example I mean
并且数据数据的整个点没有
and the whole point of data data doesn't
进来方阵幸运的
come in square matrices fortunately for
我们的数据非常经常出现
us data very very often comes in
矩阵，但列可能是
matrices but the to the columns might be
采样可能是患者和行
sampled might be patients and the rows
可能是疾病或我的意思
might be diseases or something I mean
他们是不同的空间
they're they're different spaces so
矩阵不太可能是方形的，但
matrices are not likely to be square but
无论如何我们在这里很好没关系，所以
anyway we're good here okay okay so the
行空间
row space
现在我可以回到证明
now now can I come back to the proof
因为我们想说的就是那个
because we what I want to say is that
这个基本事实的证明是
the proof of this fundamental fact is
盯着我们，但我们并没有看到它
staring at us but we don't quite see it
然而，我想看到它，所以我声称
yet and I want to see it so I claim that
这些行是行空间的基础
these rows are a basis for the row space
我们已经看到了这些专栏
and we already saw that these columns
我们的列空间基础和两个
our basis for the column space and two
在这里等于两个右两个向量或a
equals two right two vectors here or a
如果可以的话，现在可以用于列空间的基础
basis for the column space now if I can
看看为什么这会告诉我这两个
see why this shows me that these two
向量是行空间的基础
vectors are a basis for the row space
然后我有我的榜样是对的
then then I have my example is right
这两者都会给予
both both of these will give to the
列排名是行的两列
column rank is to two columns the row
等级是两行所以
rank is to two rows so
我必须解释为什么我相信这一点
I have to explain why I believe that
这两行是行的基础
these two rows are a basis for the row
空间权有我，我要证明给
space right with me I have to prove to
当我说的时候，先看看为什么会这样
see why first are there so when I say
我有什么检查基础是
basis what do I have to check basis is
这是我的关键想法
is just is the critical idea it I have
检查他们是独立的，所以我
to check that they're independent so I
没有得到太多的矢量我有
haven't got too many vectors I've got
那里还有任何额外的载体，我也是
any extra vectors in there and I also
必须检查他们的组合
have to check that their combinations
如果我这么说就产生所有的行
produce all the rows should I say that
再次那是因为那就是我的意思
again that's because that's what I'm
要检查我会检查
going to check I'm gonna check that
那些家伙很独立，你可以
those guys are independent well you can
看到他们是独立的，我是
see that they're independent and I'm
要检查那是他们的
going to check that the that their
组合产生所有这三个
combinations produce all three of these
行如果我们没有创建这些数字
rows if we didn't create those numbers
为了这个目的，但我所说的是
for this purpose but what I'm saying is
他们工作，所以我声称这是一个
they work so I claim that this is a
因为什么组合的基础
basis because what what combination of
那两行会产生这个
those two rows would produce this this
第一排是啊让我问你那个
first row yeah let me just ask you that
什么组合应该是什么数字
what combination what numbers should I
乘这两行通过获得
multiply these two rows by to get the
第一排任何两个，一个和哪里
first row of any two and one and where
你找到两个和一个吗？
do you find two and one
它坐在那里，看看我和我
it's sitting there in see what I'm and
它会再次发挥作用吗？
will it work again does three of this
加上其中一个给三个一个是的
plus one of that give three one four yes
到现在为止还挺好
so far so good
其中五个和七个看到了
does five of this and seven of that see
我在成倍增长我想我正在做矩阵
I'm multiplying I guess I'm doing matrix
乘法一种落后的等待
multiplication a sort of backward wait
或者我正在采取不同的方式
or a different different way I'm taking
第二行的组合
combinations of the rows of the second
人这是另一种方式是一个
guy that's another way that one
关于矩阵的小心
careful thing about matrix
乘法是你可以做很多的
multiplication is you can do it a lot of
各种各样的方式和方式
ways it comes out the same every way and
每路告诉你的东西，所以5
each way tells you something so 5 of
那行加上那行的7肯定了
that row plus 7 of that row sure enough
在这里，你看到那不是那样的
is here do you see that that is not like
事实证明这是真的
accident that that the proof is really
看看这个乘法C次
to look at this multiplication C times
有两种方式首先看它
are two ways look at it first as
C列的组合给出
combinations of columns of C to give the
列看第二个得到它
columns look at it second to get as
R和那些行的组合
combinations of the rows of R and that
生成行以使分解
produces the rows so that factorization
等于CR是关键的想法和
a equals C R was what's the key idea and
实际上这是我们想出来的R.
actually this R that we've come up with
有一个名字
has a name
任何人都记得足够1806这里是一个
anybody remember enough 1806 here's a
比如你们都花了1806我不是我
like have you all taken 1806 I'm no I
看到我们有多少让我们好的好
see us how many have let's yes okay good
有一段时间1806教了一个非常
for a while 1806 was taught in a very
抽象的方式我说的是发生了什么但是
abstract way I said what's going on but
无论如何，如果你在那个学期学习
anyway so if you took it that semester
你可能从未听说过专栏
you maybe never heard of the column
空间我不确定或不同
space I'm not sure or by a different
命名它有另一个名字
name it has another name
列空间的另一个名称是什么
what's its other name the column space
对于矩阵范围，我认为它是范围
of a matrix range I think it's the range
是的，是的，是的，是的，当然
yeah right right yep yep and of course
这一切都是基础
it's all this is fundamental in
数学当然是一切
mathematics so of course it everything
这里有不同的语言和
here is is has different languages and
不同的重点，但你看到了什么
different emphasis but you see what the
重点在这里好，所以你看到了
emphasis is here okay so you see the
证明等于CR只是揭示
proof that a equals C R is just reveals
一切都那么它的第一个想法
everything so it's a first idea of a
矩阵的分解
factorization of a matrix
并且，我们已经看到倍增时间为
and and we've multiplied see times are
现在我可以说因为这样
now I could just say cuz so that's
真的，你已经看到了现在的主力
really you've seen the now the main
部分的音符的1.1的点
point of section 1.1 of the notes to
想出那个因素化和那个
come up with that factorization and that
结论和，你知道为什么C有
conclusion and and and you see why C has
相同数量的列数
the same number of the number of columns
的C的温度将我们的行数和
of C will the number of rows of our and
这些是列排名和行
those are the column rank and the row
排名是的它只是非常整洁和在这里
rank yeah it's just pretty neat and here
是那些专栏的特例
was the special case where those column
空间列空间都是倍数
space the column space is all multiples
你这一行是排成一行的
of you it's a line through you the row
空间是V的倍数它是一条线
space is all multiples of V it's a line
通过V，这是基本建筑
through V and that's the basic building
阻止是啊我可以再说一点
block yeah can I just say another little
在我超越CR之前的那个词
word before I push on beyond CR that
如果你有一个巨人，这就成了
that this has become if you have a giant
矩阵像大小10到五分之一
matrix like size 10 to the fifth that's
你知道你不能把它放进去
that you know you can't put that into
快速记忆你是它的一团糟
fast memory you it's it's it's a mess
你如何处理与大小为10的矩阵
how do you deal with a matrix of size 10
当你无法处理时到第五个
to the fifth when you cannot deal with
所有的条目，这只是不
all the entries that that's just not
可能
possible
你会因此在后面的样本时
will you sample it so later in the
当然我们会做随机抽样的
course we'll be doing random sampling of
一个矩阵，你的样本怎么样？
a matrix so how could your sample a
矩阵，所以你当然有一个矩阵
matrix so you have a matrix of course
你不是在看它，因为但是
you're not looking at it because but
它是你想要得到一些典型的
it's and you want to get some typical
列好吧，这是你的自然想法
columns okay here's the natural idea you
当你拿X时，只要看看任何xx
just look at any x x when you take let X
是随机向量随机向量R和R.
be a random vector random vector R and R
因此它有M行和一列
and of so it's got M rows and one column
这是一个载体，我能说些什么
it's a vector and what can I say about
斧头
ax
它位于列空间的空间中
it's in what spaces it in column space
谢谢，这是第一个想法
thanks that was the first idea in this
在这个讲座中，ax就在专栏中
in this lecture ax is in the column
空间，所以如果你想要一个随机向量
space so if you want a random vector in
列空间我不建议它
the column space I wouldn't suggest it
只需随机选择其中一列
just randomly pick one of the columns
最好采取混合列
better to take a mixture of columns by
采取随机向量X，看着
taking a random vector X and looking at
看着斧头，如果你想要一个
looking at ax and if you wanted a
一百个随机向量你
hundred random vectors you take a
一百个随机X和那将给
hundred random X's and that would give
在很多情况下你都是个好主意
you a pretty good idea in many cases of
列空间看起来是什么样的
what what the column space looks like
这足以经常使用
that would be enough to work with often
是的好的我可以直接投入
yeah okay okay can I just throw in
另一个问题，所以斧头就在
another question so so ax is in the
列空间让我问你
column space of a let me just ask you
这个问题是ABCX就是在
this question is is ABC X is that in the
我有一个假设的列空间
column space of a suppose I have
矩阵aB和C以及向量X和I.
matrices a B and C and a vector X and I
拿他们的产品那样给我
take their product does that give me
在列空间中的某些东西是肯定的
something in the column space of a yes
对你有好处为什么你怎么知道
good for you why how do you know that
没错这就是一个时间正确的事情把
yeah it's a time something right putting
在正确的地方括号是
parentheses in the right place is the
线性代数的关键，他们没关系
key to linear algebra and they're okay
这是一个问题，只是发生在我身上和
it's a question just occurred to me and
我想好了，我想知道你是否这样做
I thought well I wonder if you'd do it
好的，所以我们还有时间成倍增加
okay so we have still time to multiply
矩阵哦我会说C
matrices oh I was going to say about C
和R所以这些是来自a的真实列
and R so these are real columns from a
但R是不直接采取的行
but R is the rows are not taken directly
从一排实际上有一个
from the rows of a actually there's a
这个名称叫做行
name for this it's called the row
减少矩阵的梯形和
reduced echelon form of the matrix and
这是一个很大的目标，在1806年它有
it's a big goal in in 1806 it has the
那里的身份然后另一个
identity there and then the other
专栏告诉你正确的
columns are tell you the right
组合yepyep另一个大
combinations yep yep another big
分解将采取列
factorization would be to take columns
从一个所以这是另一个所以我会
from from a so this is another so I'll
也许或者我们不会这样做
put maybe or and we won't be doing this
一个月
for a month
我们可以开始列列
we could start take columns of columns
a并把它们放进去看看它们是不是
of a and put them in to see if they were
独立，假设我采取了一排
independent and suppose I took rows of a
现在我要采取字面意思
now I'm going to take literally rows of
a把它们放入或放好，所以我称之为
a and put them into or well so I call it
我们的旋风或者其他东西，因为它将是一个
our twiddle or something cuz it'll be a
不同的R我会用实际不
different R I'm gonna use actually not
我不打算使用那些行但是我
I'm not going to use those rows but I'm
那将要拿两个实际的行
gonna take two actual rows of a then
这是什么，这是重要的分解
what so that's important factorization
但这不正确我不会，如果我
but it's not correct I wouldn't if I
拿了另外两行我们不会
took two other rows of our it wouldn't
工作，所以你必须放在中间
work so you have to put in the middle
你创造了一些二乘二矩阵
some two-by-two matrix you that makes it
只是你会在里面看到正确的
correct just you'll see on the in the in
第1.1节我很兴奋
that section 1.1 that I got excited and
写了一个关于看到你的页面
wrote a page about seeing you are yep
固体只是提到他好了，所以现在我
solid just mention that okay so now I'm
准备哦，我想说些什么
ready oh I wanted to say something about
课程决定了关于质量的事情但是
the course decided thing about mass but
有这个课程，所以这是怎么回事
there is this course so what's up so
有线性代数问题，但是
there be linear algebra problems but but
是什么让这个过程特别是
what makes this course special is the
其他在线和你的作业
other homeworks which are online and you
会使用让我们原则上看你
would use let's see in principle you
可以使用任何语言
could use any of the languages
MATLAB的Python这已成为
MATLAB Python which has become the
最常用于深度学习或
biggest most used for deep learning or
朱莉娅这是热门
Julia which is the hot
最后一个学期的新语言
new language and so last semester the
问题哦，所以去年发生的事情
problems oh so what happened last year
这个课程中的一切都是颂歌
well everything in this course is ode to
一位来自大学的教授
a professor who visited from University
密歇根大学教授rah-rahsRao
of Michigan professor rah-rahs Rao
谁教给了大部分的演讲的
who taught gave most of the lectures a
一年前带来了这些功课问题
year ago brought these homework problems
在线作业问题让人们如此
online homework problems so that people
带上笔记本电脑上课，我们做到了
brought laptops to class and we did
课堂上的东西，所以他曾经和
things in class and so he had had and
在EE中有非常成功的EE课程
has very successful course in EE in
密歇根州，但他从这里获得博士学位
Michigan and but he was a PhD from here
他回来后在休假，他
and he came back on a sabbatical and he
创造了这让我们开始和我们
created this got us started and we
真的欠他很多
really owe a lot to him
阿德尔曼教授也参与其中
also professor Adelman was involved with
这个课程，你可能会知道他
this course and you may be know that he
创造了朱莉娅有多少人喜欢知道什么
created julia how many like know what
朱莉娅很棒哦
julia is Oh wonderful
这将使他的一天，他告诉我每一个
that will make his day he tells me every
时间我看到朱莉娅很好，我告诉他
time I see him Julia's good and I tell
不管怎么说，我相信它还可以
him I believe it ok anyway and it's
成为1806年的教授约翰逊
become the professor Johnson in 1806 has
使用朱莉娅和每学期的斯蒂芬
used Julia and every semester Stephen
约翰逊在第一周给出了一个
Johnson gives in the first week a
关于朱莉娅的教程，所以他就是这样
tutorial on Julia and so he's that's
安排我答应告诉你
arranged and I promised to tell you
哪里哪里的时候是这样的，我认为，如果
where where when that is so I think if
你不知道任何关于朱莉娅尝试
you don't know anything about Julia try
去星期五的Stata吧
to go it's in Stata it's on Friday at
5:005:00到7:00所以Julia来自
5:00 5:00 to 7:00 so Julia from
约翰逊教授
professor Johnson
所以他多次这样做了
so he's done this multiple times he's
擅长
good at it
所以这是McQueen的哦，但我我猜
so that's McQueen Oh yet what I I guess
我希望你有一个选项，
I'm hoping that you'll have an option to
使用三种语言中的任何一种，但是
use all any of the three languages but
我们提供的在线产品
the the the online thing that we give
你是朱莉娅创建的教授
you was created in Julia so professor
去年春天，饶必须学习朱莉娅
Rao had to learn Julia last spring and
虽然他们的班级也做了，而且有
though their class did too and there was
关于它的一定程度的婊子
a certain amount of bitching about it
但我想也许只有一个例外
but I think with maybe one exception who
仍然有一个A我们每个人都有点
still got an A we everybody was kind of
好吧，是兰欣茱莉亚
okay and was glad to learn Julia and
饶教授现在完全使用朱莉娅
professor Rao now uses Julia entirely
像这样，他是创造上匝道一个新的与
like so he's creating a new on-ramp with
朱莉娅
Julia
顺便说一下，MATLAB刚发布了一个
MATLAB by the way has just issued an
我会告诉他们深入学习的过程
on-ramp to deep learning that I'll tell
你可能会得到一个MATLAB
you about and probably get a MATLAB
有数学人的工作要说
somebody from math works to to say
关于它的事情是的，所以这是什么
something about it yeah so that's what's
即便如此，我们还不太清楚
coming that we don't quite know exactly
我们将如何组织这些家庭作业
how we'll organize those homeworks would
只需要拿第一个，看看有什么
just take the first one and see see what
发生
happens
所以我肯定会说更多
so I'll certainly say more about
作业的时候甚至可能
homeworks when when the maybe even
周五但还有其他问题
Friday but are there other questions
我应该这么回答，因为有些人
that I should answer so because some
人们会好好想的我会去
people will be thinking okay am I going
要做到这一点，还是我要坐六点哦
to do this or am I gonna sit in six oh
三个六或其他一些深入的课程
three six or some other course in deep
学习你的想法和你
learning anything on your mind and you
可以给我发电子邮件，以便我们有一个恒星
can email me so we will have a stellar
网站，你会看到所有的TAS
site and you'll see all the the TAS are
仍然被命名但是精彩
still to be named but the wonderful
拿东西的是本科生
thing is that undergraduates who took
这门课程去年是志愿者
this course last year are volunteering
为你们做分级，所以他们会
to be graders for you guys so they will
知道那些在线作业是什么
know what those online homeworks were
关于它没问题，这就是它的意思
about it okay so that's what's it's a
排序第一个字将会发生什么
sort of first word about what's coming
关于语言还可以
about about the language okay
我要完成一个非常重要的事情
I'm gonna finish by a very important
主题乘以一次B哦看
topic multiplying a times B oh look
清洁板，所以我知道我想要倍增
cleaning board so I know I want multiply
将矩阵乘以向量
multiply a matrix by a vector
好的，大家都知道怎么做你
okay everybody knows how to do it you
排成一排让你排成一排
take a row of a so you take a row of a
你拿了一列B然后你就拿走了
and you take a column of B and you take
这个点产品让你得到点积
that dot product so you get dot product
行行得到列行点再次
row row got column row dot that's again
低级别对初学者来说还可以，但是我们
low level like okay for beginners but we
想要看到矩阵乘法a
want to see that matrix multiplication a
B更深入，更深层次
B in a deeper way and the deeper way is
列乘以行的行列
columns times rows columns of a rows of
B列时间排得很好我们有一个
B columns times rows well we had a
列是右边一行就是这个
column times a row right that was this
排名我们有列时间的例子
rank one example we had our column times
一行，它产生了一个矩阵和
a row and it produced a matrix and
这就是它的样子，它的排名
that's what it looks like and it's rank
是一个所以那些是什么
was one so those are what
我们有一个好的所以它是一个组合
we have a good so it's a combination of
它非常像斧头我真的很公正
it's very like ax I'm really just
将斧头的想法扩展到B所以这样
extending the ax idea to a B so so this
这是旧的方式，一种新的方式是列
this is the old way a new way is columns
所以有K列它会成倍增加
so there's column K it will multiply
果然它会倍增r好吧
sure enough it multiplies r okay
每个人都认为会发生这种情况
everybody sees that it will happen that
如果你这样做的方式，你做的方式
way if you do it the old way when you do
这里的东西的点积
a dot product of something here
你正在做这些事
something here you're doing these
乘法和当你击中列时
multiplications and when you hit column
K在这里你打了K行所以这些
K here you hit row K there so so these
是连接所以我得到的东西
are connected so so I get things like
B和I的时间R好的列K.
column K of a times R okay of B and I
我不知道你的记号
don't know what notation to you so I
只是写了他们写的话好吧
just wrote them wrote the words okay
但现在这一块的的
but now that's one piece of the of the
最终答案的乐趣B是一个
fun of the final answer a B that's a
排名像建筑物一样的一块
rank one piece that's a like a building
阻止所以我从k等于1汤姆1
block so I add from k equal 1 tom 1
时间排一列一列Row
times Row one column one of a times Row
其中一个B加da加列K加和
one of B plus da plus column K plus and
当然，我有时会停止它
of course I stop it column in of a times
因此它是外部产品的总和
row in so it's a sum of outer products
因此，每个人都会看到一笔款项
some of so everybody sees a sum because
II列1列第1列K列
I I have column 1 times Row 1 column K
时间Rok称他们n次排入和
times R ok call them n times row in and
然后我添加那些它只是
then I add those pieces it's just the
那里有X2矩阵B的推广
generalization of a X 2 matrix B there
所以这是它的总和
so it's the sum of
B的Roque的m'kay流氓，也许我们
m'kay rogue of a Roque of B and maybe we
我们应该检查那给了我们的
should we check that that gives us the
正确的回答也许我不会那么做
right answer or maybe I won't do that
在这里，但它就是我们所做的一切
here but it it's it's all we're doing is
相同的乘法在不同的
the same multiplications in a different
订单实际上让我们退出一个
order actually let's just quit with one
我们可以弄清楚有多少
minute we can figure out how many
乘法有多少
multiplications are there how many
乘以做一个M乘n矩阵a
multiplications to do a M by n matrix a
时间是P矩阵B的结束，所以是a
time's the end by P matrix B so that's a
次数B个别数字
times B how many individual numbers
因为这是决定它的成本
because this is determine the cost of it
我们需要多少个数字
how many numbers would we need well
假设我们在内心深处做旧的方式
suppose we do it the old way by in inner
产品行x列那么多少怎么样
product row x column so how many how
很多次乘法我做了一次
many multiplications to do a row times I
给他们打电话，得到的一个条目
call them and get one entry in the
回答n右边的行有长度
answer n right the row has length in the
列的长度为n次乘法
column has length in n multiplications
这是N，现在有多少人这样做了
so that's N and now how many of those do
我必须做MP，因为它的大小
I have to do MP because what's the size
这个答案大小的答案
of this answer the size of this answer
是的，所以如果我这样做，他们就可以了
is n by P okay so if I do they do it in
那个旧命令就像n乘法一样
that old order like n multiplications to
做一个点产品，我有这么多
do a dot product and I've got this many
在答案中点了产品，所以我得到了M.
dot products in the answer so I've got M
和P多次乘法现在假设我
and P multiple multiplies now suppose I
这样做
do it this way
做多少次乘法
how many multiplications to do one of
那些家伙将一列乘以一列
those guys to multiply a column by a row
将此列乘以一行
to multiply a column by a row this this
是一个M，这是1乘P1
is an M by one and this is a 1 by P one
第一列
column one row
多少次乘法那家伙在
how many multiplications for that guy in
P和那些排名的人中有多少人
P and how many of those ranked ones do I
你必须得到它的MP时间
have to do you got it it's MP times in
现在是另一种方式是n次
now it's the other way was was n times
MP所以给出相同的答案MNp
MP so it gives the same answer MN p
事实上，他们完全一样
mostly in fact they're exactly the same
乘法只是一个不同的顺序
multiplications just a different order
好的，我们在155感谢您的光临
okay we're at 155 thanks for coming
today I'll talk more about the class and
今天我会更多地谈论课程和
关于星期五的线性代数谢谢
about linear algebra on Friday thank you